Alexis McKay



PROFILE

Sometimes down to Earth, sometimes well above the clouds. I have an unique love and fascination for nature, visible and invisible. I believe that by learning about the stars in the universe, we can learn more about ourselves. I am empowered by the knowledge I have gained through my education and life experiences so far. I am also humbled by just how much there still is for me to learn. Feeling important in an infinite universe is a difficult task, but I think I am managing it quite nicely.

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Pronouns: she/her/hers

CONTACT DETAILS

@ almc6720@colorado.edu

② (303) 492-5002 (work phone)

⊠ 2414 Regent Dr, Boulder, CO 80309 (work address)

SKILLS

- Python, R Studio, Excel
- Digital Sky 2, Laser Fantasy
- Group collaboration and communication
- · Independent focus
- Leadership
- Adaptivity
- Determination
- Resilience
- Passion

WORK EXPERIENCE

PLANETARIUM NAVIGATOR at Fiske Planetarium

February 2024-present Boulder, CO

⋄ Follow safe theater protocols and create welcoming environment for the public to experience astronomy education, music shows, and more.

BANQUET CAPTAIN at Wedgewood Weddings

September 2021 - September 2023 Boulder, CO

♦ Banquet staff representative and line of communication between guests, staff and vendors at events such as weddings, graduations, birthday parties, etc.

CAMP COUNSELOR at ABLE to Sail Youth Empowerment Camp

June 2020 - August 2022 Longmont, CO

 \diamond Facilitate a kids camp that uses metaphors in sailing to teach about selfworth and growth.

HOSTESS at B.O.B.S Diner

September 2017 - May 2020 Louisville, CO

♦ Provide excellent customer service and accommodate to guests' needs at a small local diner.

EDUCATION

(IN PROGRESS) BACHELOR OF ARTS AND SCIENCES IN ASTRONOMY
University of Colorado Boulder.

August 2020-present

Areas of focus: star life cycles, evolution of galaxies, space policy

(IN PROGRESS) BACHELOR OF ARTS AND SCIENCES IN PSYCHOLOGY
University of Colorado Boulder.

August 2020 – present

♦ Areas of focus: ongoing mental health crisis, representation in STEM

(IN PROGRESS) MINOR IN MATHEMATICS University of Colorado Boulder.

August 2020 – present

Areas of focus: statistics, math education

HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA Centaurus High School

August 2016 – May 2020

AWARDS

HELEN MCLORAINE SCHOLARSHIP

2020, 2021, 2022

 \diamond Awarded to promising former foster youth aspiring to pursue an education after high school

BE BRIGHT SCHOLARSHIP

2020

 \diamond Awarded to former foster youth pursuing an education at the University of Colorado Boulder

BRIGHT FUTURES AWARD

2020

Awarded to foster youth that demonstrate resilience and determination

HOBBIES

Outdoors: stargazing, skateboarding, snowboarding, hiking, sailing, gardening, swimming, road tripping

Music: attending concerts, raves and festivals, singing, viola, guitar *Gaming:* Nintendo, old school arcade games, pinball